[SPEAKER_02]: into the industry, discussing all things HVAC.
[SPEAKER_02]: from storytelling to technical discussion.
[SPEAKER_02]: Enjoy the show.
[SPEAKER_02]: All right, Rachel, the first question I'm gonna ask you is
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you come up with the name Miss Mini Split?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was doing a lot of mini splits at the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was...
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm trying to think of an Instagram.
[SPEAKER_01]: I decided to make an Instagram.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I just happened to be doing many splits, and I was like, oh, that's
[SPEAKER_01]: That sounds catchy.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what I came up with.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we're going to talk the audience that's listening right now.
[SPEAKER_02]: now we're going to talk about the installation of a mini split.
[SPEAKER_02]: and Rachel and I will go through it together.
[SPEAKER_02]: And if you guys are new to the trade newer to the trader
[SPEAKER_02]: or you're just looking for tips to make your installs go a little bit
[SPEAKER_02]: better.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm sure the conversation will help with that.
[SPEAKER_02]: So...
[SPEAKER_02]: You got a car seat in the back of your work truck.
[SPEAKER_02]: explain so.
[SPEAKER_02]: Like obviously you have a
[SPEAKER_02]: a young child and you got to maybe drop off to
[SPEAKER_02]: daycare or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, exactly.
[SPEAKER_02]: Once in a while on your way to work.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, that's exactly the routine.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've seen a post where you actually brought your kid to work.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did that all come about?
[SPEAKER_02]: Because that's interesting to me, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, so I made
[SPEAKER_00]: my instagram miss minisplit in the summer of
[SPEAKER_00]: 2023 by that time I
[SPEAKER_00]: I've already been doing HVAC for like 10 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: All right, and before that, you know
[SPEAKER_01]: just been out here doing my things.
[SPEAKER_01]: not on social media.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I think I was pregnant or I had just had my baby.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah that's right I was pregnant with my second kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: by the time I made my Miss Mini Split Instagram.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so I was kind of like working part time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the only reason why I was working part-time was
[SPEAKER_01]: because I had already been working full-
[SPEAKER_01]: time.
[SPEAKER_01]: for a bunch of general contractors.
[SPEAKER_01]: had all these customers and I told
[SPEAKER_01]: them and I tried to keep telling them, you know,
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not working right now, and they would just
[SPEAKER_01]: Beg me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Say, please come, just bring your baby.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, it'll be fine and I'm like, ah, I don't
[SPEAKER_01]: I really like doing that, but...
[SPEAKER_01]: you know, sometimes some customers.
[SPEAKER_01]: You just got to take care of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: So it got to the point.
[SPEAKER_01]: where I was like, fine, I'll just bring my kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: and I would bring my mom with me so she would kind of help.
[SPEAKER_01]: watch my kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sometimes it was as young as three months old.
[SPEAKER_01]: So she would be there watching the kid while I work and I would take a break.
[SPEAKER_01]: break.
[SPEAKER_01]: you know, take care of my kid, you know, change her diaper.
[SPEAKER_01]: or feed her and that sort of thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Interesting.
[SPEAKER_02]: The struggles of being a mom sometimes, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I shouldn't say I get it because I'm not a mom, but I
[SPEAKER_02]: I got three kids of my own so I get
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah, then the whole
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I get the whole family dynamic and having to
[SPEAKER_02]: balance your life and struggle and make sure that your kids
[SPEAKER_02]: come first, but you also got to
[SPEAKER_02]: work and maintain a living.
[SPEAKER_02]: and to bring in that income so you can buy food and
[SPEAKER_02]: like a home and a bed for yourself and your kids and stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: too.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I commend the fact that you worked
[SPEAKER_02]: that hard to make it work.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pretty cool.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, where are you located?
[SPEAKER_02]: You're located in California, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, San Diego.
[SPEAKER_02]: San Diego, okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: So when it comes to, you're doing a lot of mini splits.
[SPEAKER_02]: So is that?
[SPEAKER_02]: side of the industry taken off a lot in
[SPEAKER_02]: California and San Diego like the mini split.
[SPEAKER_02]: side of things?
[SPEAKER_01]: And the reason for that is...
[SPEAKER_01]: because of the housing crisis out here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And because of the housing crisis, there's a huge
[SPEAKER_01]: push for affordable housing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, if you want affordable housing, you have to build
[SPEAKER_01]: it affordably to begin with.
[SPEAKER_01]: or else you can't rent it out for an affordable price.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so part of that is finding affordable trades.
[SPEAKER_01]: of affordable HVAC systems.
[SPEAKER_01]: and so there is a huge demand for Mini Split.
[SPEAKER_01]: systems right now out here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, well, it makes sense because if you think about a centralized
[SPEAKER_02]: system.
[SPEAKER_02]: going into a unit or...
[SPEAKER_02]: whatever it is that how they're
[SPEAKER_02]: they're building or dividing the spaces.
[SPEAKER_02]: duck work and all that, then you got to frame around it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_02]: That costs a lot of money.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was just speaking to somebody that wants.
[SPEAKER_02]: that got a 1400 square foot home.
[SPEAKER_02]: that they're building and
[SPEAKER_02]: the quotes to get duck work and a furnace and all that in.
[SPEAKER_02]: is upwards of $20,000 or more.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, no
[SPEAKER_02]: you could throw in a mini-split for way less than that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_02]: So it makes sense what you're saying, so it's a lot more.
[SPEAKER_02]: affordable to the
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess the general contractor that's putting it in.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the thing with a mini-split these days
[SPEAKER_02]: is they're very reliable like the technology behind